莫妮卡
Monica?
现在几点
What time is it?
九点
Nine.
可是外面还很黑
But it's dark out.
那是因为你老睡到中午  傻瓜
That's because you always sleep till noon, silly.
九点就是这么黑
This is what nine looks like.
那我该梳洗一下
I guess I'll get washed up then.
准备看日出
Watch that sunrise.
我不想再偷偷摸摸了
I'm getting tired of sneaking around.
我也是
I know me too.
不如我们去外面度周末吧
Y'know what if we went away for a whole weekend?
就没人打扰我们了
Y'know we'd have no interruptions
还可以整日脱得光光
and we could be naked the entire time.
整个周末  那可有好多脱光光
All weekend? That's a whole lot of naked.
我可以说我去开会
Yeah, I can say that I have a conference
你就说去参加厨师什么会
and you can say you have a chef thing.
我一直想参加
I've always wanted to go to
新泽西的烹饪大会
this culinary fair that they have in Jersey!
很好  不过你去的不是那里
Okay. You know you're not, though.
-走吧  -好  等等
- Let's go. - Okay. Wait.
乔伊怎么办
What about Joey?
知道我这周末要干嘛吗
Hey, guess what I'm doing this weekend!
我要去新泽西参加烹饪大会
I'm going to this culinary fair in New Jersey.
奇怪  钱德勒刚说要去那里开会
How weird! Chandler just said he's got a conference there.
真有意思
That's funny.
钱德勒应该可以去
Seems like Chandler's conference could've been...
康涅狄格或佛蒙特州开会
...in Connecticut or Vermont.
我又不能决定在哪里开会
I'm not in charge of where the conference is held.
难道你希望大家认为我造假吗  我可没说慌
Do you want people to think it's fake? It's a real conference.
瑞秋在吗  我有话跟她说
Is Rachel here? I gotta talk to her.
她出去逛街了
No, she's out shopping.
-可恶  -怎么了
- Damn! - What's going on?
我叫艾蜜莉来
I told Emily to come.
所以我得赶快跟瑞秋说
And I just need to, you know, talk to Rachel about it.
等等
Wait a minute.
艾蜜莉来了之后  你真的就不再见瑞秋了吗
When Emily comes, you're just, you're not gonna see Rachel anymore?
我现在只能专心想着
Well look, I'm just trying to focus on
我可以见我老婆
the "I get to see my wife," part, all right?
不去想我快胃溃疡的事
...and not on the part that makes me do this.
你们再也不能共处一室了吗
So you guys are, you're never gonna be in the same room together?
这怎么可能
How is that even gonna work?
我也不知道  我是说
I have no idea. I mean...
但我保证  我一定会想到办法
But I assure you, I will figure it out.
看起来实在不可能
Doesn't seem like it's going to work.
嗨  大家好
Hi, guys.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们正要帮莫妮卡翻床垫
We're flipping Monica's mattress.
我认为应该先抬起来再翻过来
So I'm thinking, basically, we pick it up and then we flip it.
这方法比我的主意好
That's better than my way.
你们要不要顺便帮我翻下
Oh okay, hey guys, would you flip mine too?
受不了
Oh, man.
看啊  我妈寄信来了
Oh, look! A letter from my mom.
瑞秋
So, Rach?
你知道艾蜜莉要来  对吗
You know how Emily's coming, right?
是  我知道啊
Oh, yeah. I know.
听得到吗
Can you hear anything?
当然  刚刚有人说"听得到吗"
Yeah, somebody just said, "Can you hear anything?"
乔伊的大屁股
Hey, Joey's ass.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
记得上次他们吵架分手时
Well, remember when they got in that big fight and broke up,
我们困在房里没东西可吃吗
...and we were stuck here all night with no food or anything?
罗斯在婚礼上说出瑞秋的名字后
When Ross said "Rachel" at the wedding,
我猜旧戏可能会重演
I figured it was gonna happen again.
所以我在这里藏了这些东西
So I hid this in here.
有糖果  填字游戏
Candy bars, crossword puzzles...
疯狂字谜  我要
Mad Libs! Mine!
保险套
Condoms?
谁晓得会在这里待多久
You don't know how long we'll be in here.
搞不好我们还得负责繁衍人类后代
We may have to repopulate the Earth.
戴保险套就是用来繁衍后代的
And condoms are the way to do that?
总之  有个关键问题
Anyway, it all boils down to this.
上次我跟艾蜜莉通电话
The last time I talked to Emily...
天啊  我的狗死了
Oh, my God! My dog died!
什么
What?
我家的狗  拉普死了
Our dog! LaPooh!
拉普还活着吗
LaPooh's still alive?
我妈说它被冰激凌车撞到
It says he was hit by an ice cream truck and dragged for nine...
还被拖了19条街
...teen blocks!
-我的天啊  -亲爱的  我们听到你在哭
- Oh, my God. - Sweetie, we heard you crying.
-拜托别哭了  -拉普出事了
- Please don't cry. - It's LaPooh!
现在你为拉普难过  等下这就不算什么了
I know, it's LaPooh right now but it'll get better.
不敢相信  我们到了
I can't believe it! We're here!
枕头上还放巧克力  我最喜欢这样了
Chocolates on the pillows! I love that!
那你应该跟乔伊住  到处都有巧克力糖
You should live with Joey. Rolos everywhere.
我马上就好
Okay, be right back.
万岁
Oh, yes!
莫妮卡  快来  正在转播警匪公路追逐战
Monica, get in here. There's a high-speed car chase on!
我们要换房间
We're switching rooms.
天啊  他们给了我们玻璃杯
Oh, dear God! They gave us glasses!
杯子上有口红印
No, they gave us glasses with lipstick on them!
如果连杯子都没换
If they didn't change the glasses,
谁知道还有哪些东西没换
who knows what else they didn't change?
拜托  我只是希望过个完美的周末
Come on, i just want this weekend to be perfect,
-换个房间嘛  -好的
- we can change rooms, can't we? - Okay.
好吧  要换快换  五号直升机刚跟丢了
Okay, but let's do it now, because Chopper 5 just lost it's feed!
那个...
Hey, so uh,
记得我上次有事要告诉你吗
y'know how there's something I wanted to talk to you about?
对
Oh, yeah.
你知道
Well,
我很希望跟艾蜜莉和好
y'know how I'm trying to work things out with Emily.
不过  还有
Well, there's this...
一件事
...one thing.
好吧
Okay.
我要说了
Here goes.
我答应她
I made a promise that...
-什么  -你在流鼻血
- What? - Your nose is bleeding.
-天啊  -你在流鼻血
- Oh, God! - You're bleeding.
别又来了  我祖父过世时也一样
Oh, not again. This happened when my grandfather died.
对不起
Sorry.
真恶心
Gross.
好了  对不起  你刚要说什么
Okay. So I'm sorry. What did you want to tell me?
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
好的  我
Okay. I...
我不能再见你了
I can't see you anymore.
我知道  真离谱  我也看不到你
I know, it's ridiculous. I can't see you, either.
你们可能会喜欢这间房
I think you'll find this room more to your liking.
太好了
Okay, great.
听说他只剩下一半的汽油
They say he's only got half a tank left.
一半  那还可以跑很久呢
Half a tank? We still got a lots of high-speed chasing to do!
我们还得换房间
We're switching rooms again.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
这间房是花园景观  我们订的是观海房
This has a garden view room. We paid for an ocean view room.
只剩一间观海房  可是你们不喜欢
Our last ocean-view room was unacceptable to you.
不好意思  我可以跟你谈一下吗
Excuse me. Can I talk to you over here for just a second?
-钱德勒  -来了
- Chandler! - Yeah.
这些小人想占我们便宜
Look, these clowns are trying to take us for a ride
我不能让他们得逞
and I'm not gonna let 'em.
咱们可不是好欺负的
We're not a couple of suckers.
说得好  大姐头
I hear you, Mugsy.
这些房间都还不错
But look, all these rooms are fine okay?
你赶快选定  让我可以看...
Can you just pick one so I can watch
让我可以和你一起好好度过完美的周末
have a perfect, magical weekend together with you.
我喜欢这间
Okay, this one I like!
没了  没了  结束了  可恶
Nothing. Nothing. It's over. Damn it!
竟然没有延长时间
This is regularly scheduled programming!
可以关掉电视吗
Can we turn the TV off?
难道整个周末都要看电视吗
Do we really want to spend the weekend like this?
抱歉  我是不是妨碍你换房间了
I'm sorry. Am I getting in the way of the room-switching fun?
你火大可别怪到我身上
Don't blame me for wigging tonight.
否则该怪谁
Oh, who should I blame?
任劳任怨拖着行李跑了十间房的行李员吗
The nice bell man who had to drag out luggage to 10 different rooms?
或许该怪那个以为用半箱汽油
I don't know, how about the idiot who thought
就可以从阿尔巴尼跑到加拿大的白痴
he could drive from Albany to Canada on a half a tank of gas!
不要说死者的坏话
Do not speak ill of the dead.
我们出来是为了过浪漫周末
We're supposed to be spending a romantic weekend together.
你到底是怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
我只是想看点电视  有什么大不了的
I just want to watch a little television. What's the big deal.
放轻松点  老妈
Jeez, relax, Mom.
你说什么
What did you say?
我说  放轻松  莫妮卡
I said, "Jeez, relax, Mon."
-嘿  什么事  -嘿
- Hey, what's up? - Hey.
瑞秋  我一直有话要告诉你
Rachel, I've been wanting to tell you something for and while now
我非说不可
and I really, I just have to get it out.
说吧  什么事
Okay. All right. What's up?
你上次说
Y'know how you told me
我应该不惜代价挽救婚姻
I should do whatever it takes to fix my marriage?
对  我叫你答应艾蜜莉的所有要求
Yeah, I told you to give Emily whatever she wants.
建议不错
And while that was good advice,
不过你得知道她开的条件
you should know that what she wants...
是什么
Yeah?
就是叫我永远不能再见你
...is for me not to see you anymore.
她疯了吗  你才做不到
That's crazy! You can't do that.
你要怎么告诉她
What are you going to tell her?
天啊
Oh, my God!
你已经答应了  对吗
You already agreed to this, haven't you?
我知道自己很恶劣
It's awful, I know.
我感觉很糟糕
I mean I feel terrible but
这是我挽救婚姻的唯一方法
I have to do this if I want my marriage to work.
我必须让这段婚姻成功  我没得选择
And I do. I have to make this marriage work. I have to.
但是好在
But the good thing is,
在她来之前  我们还可以见面
we can still see each other until she gets here.
我真幸运  天啊
Lucky me! Oh, my God!
这真是好消息  罗斯
That is good news, Ross!
自从拉普过世之后这是最大的好消息
I think that's the best news I've heard since LaPooh died!
你不知道我有多难过
You have no idea what a nightmare this has been.
这个选择太难了
This is so hard.
是吗  真的吗  罗斯
Oh, yeah, really? Is it, Ross?
我可以为你减轻压力
Let me just make this little easier for you.
你做什么
What are you doing?
-摔门而去  -瑞秋  这是你的家
- Storming out. - Rachel, it's your apartment.
是吗  知道我有多生气了吗
Yeah? Well, that's how mad I am!
臭巧克力糖
Damn Rolos!
你回来了  开会怎么样
You're back! How was your conference?
糟透了  我一直在跟...同事吵架
It was terrible. I fought with my colleagues the entire time.
你有没有搞错
Are you kidding with this?
那么整个周末都泡汤了吗
So your weekend was a total bust?
也不会  我看到唐纳·川普等电梯
No, I got to see Donald Trump waiting for an elevator.
-嗨  -你也回来了
- Hi. - You're back too.
是的  钱德勒  可以出来一下吗
Yeah. Umm, Chandler can I talk to you outside for just a second?
-烹饪大会好玩吗  -糟透了
- How was your chef thing? - It was awful.
有些人根本不会欣赏美食
I guess some people just don't appreciate really good food.
可能食物开始吃起来很美味
Well, maybe it was the kind of food that tasted good at first
吃下去却害人上吐下泻
but then made everybody vomit and have diarrhea.
钱德勒
Chandler!
莫妮卡
Monica!
好了  饭店费用多少
Okay, I'd like to know how much the room was
我要付我那一半
because I'd like to pay my half.
很好  三百块
Fine. $300.
三百块
$300?
就想成每间房二十五块
Just think of it as $25 per room.
你们鬼叫什么
What are you guys woofing about?
钱德勒从我皮包里偷了二十块
Chandler stole a 20 from my purse!
不是吧
No!
知道吗  现在回头想想
You know what? Now that I think about it...
我老没二十块  而你
...I constantly find myself without 20s, and you...
皮夹里倒是很多
...always have lots.
你们应该看看她当时的表情
You should've seen the look on her face.
我不希望瑞秋恨我  我不知道该怎么办
I don't want Rachel to hate me. I don't know what to do.
-你要听我的建议吗  -请说
- You want my advice? - Yes. Please.
-你听了一定不高兴  -没关系
- You won't like it. - That's okay.
你决定结婚太仓促了
You got married too fast.
-这算哪门子建议  -看吧
- That's not advice. - I told you.
我去洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
要是有人叫我别见你们其中一个
Man, if anyone asked me to give up any of you,
-我绝对办不到  -我也不行
- I don't think I can do it. - Me neither.
或许我可以
Maybe I could do it.
我知道你们听说了罗斯跟我的事情
Look, I know you guys heard about the whole thing with me and Ross,
我已经烦了一整天
but you know, I've been obsessing about it all day
请你们别再提起了
and I'd just love not to talk about it. All right?
我不知道这算不算提起
I don't know if this falls under that category...
不过罗斯就在后面
...but Ross is right back there.
-那才不是罗斯  -不是那个
- That's not Ross. - Not that guy.
不过很像
He does look like him, though.
罗斯去洗手间了
Okay, Ross is in the bathroom.
天啊  开始了
Oh, my God! It's happening.
现在就这样了  我就像阿吉
It's already started. I'm Kip.
你才不是阿吉
Yeah, you're not Kip.
你知道阿吉是谁吗
Do you even know who Kip is?
管他呢  你是瑞秋
Who cares? You're Rachel.
阿吉是谁
Who's Kip?
阿吉是我以前的室友  也跟大家很好
Kip, my old roommate. Y'know we all used to hang out together.
那个可怜的混蛋
Oh, that poor bastard.
你们跟我说过那件事  他跟莫妮卡约会过
See, you told me the story. He and Monica dated.
分手后  他们没办法共处一室
When they broke up they couldn't even be in the same room together
你们都答应继续做他的朋友
you all promised you'd stay his friend.
结果呢  他从此遭到排挤
And what happened? He got phased out.
-我们才不会排挤你  -一定会
- You're not gonna be phased out. - Of course I am.
你们不会排挤罗斯
It won't happen to Ross.
因为他是你哥哥  你的大学室友
He's your brother, he's your college roommate.
迟早有人会离开这个小圈圈
You know it was just a matter of time before someone had to leave the group.
我以前还以为走的是菲比
I just always assumed Phoebe would be the one to go.
亲爱的  你住得远  又不是谁的亲戚
Honey, come on. You live far away, you're not related.
很快就会被淡忘
You lift right out.
嘿  宾先生
Hey, Mr. Bing.
你住的饭店打电话来了
That hotel you stayed at called.
说在你房间捡到睫毛夹
Said someone left an eyelash curler in your room.
是我的
Yes, that was mine.
我以为你钓上哪个女生
'Cause I figured you'd hooked up with some girl
她忘了带走
and she'd left it there.
这种说法的确比较合理
That would have made more sense.
我感觉都快要不认识你了
You know, I don't even feel like I know you anymore man!
听着  我只问你一次就好
All right, look, I'm just going to ask you this one time.
无论你怎么说  我都相信你
Whatever you say, I'll believe you.
你是不是去
Were you or were you not...
参加了同性恋邮轮行
...on a gay cruise?
菲比
Phoebe!
我不该说大家会淡忘你
I'm sorry about the whole "lifting out" thing.
你得跟着我
You gotta come with me.
-去哪里  -跟着我就对了
- Come where? - Wherever I go.
我们可以重组一个朋友圈
You and me, we'll start a new group.
我跟你才是最好的
We're the best ones.
好吧  不过记得拉乔伊入伙
Okay, but try to get Joey too.
菲比  我可以跟瑞秋单独谈谈吗
Pheebs, do you mind if I speak to Rachel alone for a sec?
当然
Sure.
再见  罗斯
Bye, Ross.
永远不见了
Forever.
-嗨  -嗨
-Hi. - Hi.
你来做什么  这不是违反规定吗
What are you here? Isn't this against the rules?
我跟莫妮卡谈过了
I talked to Monica.
是我做的这个选择
Look, I'm the one who made the choice.
我害大家必须要改变
I'm the one who's making things change.
所以离开的应该是我
So I should be the one to, you know, step back.
-罗斯  -真的没关系
- Ross. - No, no, it's okay. Really.
很多人只有在感恩节才见到妹妹
Plenty of people just see their sisters at Thanksgiving...
同学会才见到大学室友
just see their college roommates at reunions...
在"汉堡王"才见到乔伊
...just see Joey at Burger King.
这样你舒服一点了吗
Is that better?
一点也没有
No, it's not better.
我还是见不到你
I still don't get to see you.
换作你会怎么做  如果你是我
What would you do? Rach, if you were me,
你会怎么做
what would you do?
首先  我在婚礼上就不会说错名字
Well, for starters I would've said the right name at my wedding!
真不敢相信会这样
I can't believe this happening.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我也知道
I know that too.
瑞秋
Hey, Rach?
抱歉打扰
Sorry to interrupt,
菲比说我们要去哪里...
but Phoebe said you want to talk to me about a trip or something?
我来拿...
I just came over to drop off...
没事
...nothing.
上周末实在是差劲吧
So that weekend kinda sucked, huh?
没错
Yeah, it did.
那我想我们到此结束了
So I guess this is over?
什么
What?
我是说你跟我  反正迟早得结束
You know, you and me. I mean, it had to end sometime.
为什么
Why exactly?
因为我们上周末吵架啊
Because of the weekend. We had a fight.
钱德勒  你疯了吗
Chandler, that's crazy.
如果你每次吵架就分手
If you give up every time you'd have a fight with someone
交往大概不会超过...
...you'd never be with anyone longer than...
原来如此
Ohhh!
那么  我们没有分手吗
So, this isn't over?
你真可爱
You are so cute!
当然没有  我们只是吵架
No, no. It was a fight.
吵过之后就算了  根本没什么好担心
You deal with it and you move on. It's nothing to freak out about.
真的吗  太好了
Really? Okay, great!
欢迎加入成熟恋人行列
Welcome to an adult relationship.
我们算是恋人吗
We're in a relationship?
恐怕是
I'm afraid so.
好的
Okay.
莫妮卡  听说你开会时看到了唐纳·川普
Monica, I heard you saw Donald Trump at your convention.
我看到他在等电梯
Yeah, I saw him waiting for an elevator.
瑞秋  能借你的睫毛夹吗  我的不见了
Rach, can I borrow your eyelash curler? I think I lost mine.
好的  在厕所
Yeah, it's in the bathroom.
乔伊  我能跟你谈谈吗
Joey, can I talk to you for a second?
是
Yes.
没错
你
You?
跟你
And you?
但是你不能告诉别人  还没人知道
Yes, but you cannot tell anyone. No one knows.
可是怎么会  何时的事
But how? When?
-要从伦敦说起  -伦敦
- It happened in London. - In London!
我们没告诉大家
The reason we didn't tell anyone
是因为不想小题大做
was because we didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
可这的确是大事  我非告诉谁不可
But it is a big deal! I have to tell someone!
不行  你不能说
No-no-no-no-no! You can't!
求你了
Please, please,
我们现在还无法面对大家都知道这事
we just don't want to deal with telling everyone, okay?
求求你千万不要说出去
Just promise you won't tell.
好吧
All right.
天哪  太不可思议了
Man, this is unbelievable!
太好了
I mean, it's great!
可是
But...
我知道  的确很棒
I know. It's great!
我可不想看到这一幕
I don't want to see that!
我们真是太蠢了
We're so stupid.
你知道他们在做什么吗
Do you know what's going on in there?
他们想抢走乔伊
They're trying to take Joey!
网球界最有名的菲比叫做杀球菲比
"The most popular Phoebe in tennis is called the overhand Phoebe.
如果赢了  就得在对手的菲比上扇巴掌说
If you win, you must slap your opponent on the Phoebe and say,
"嗨  菲比"
'Hi, Phoebe!'"
真有意思  很好玩
That's cute. We really all enjoyed it.
-但是这不算  -不算什么
- But you know it doesn't count. - Count for what?
疯狂字谜不是这么玩的
Just count in our heads as good Mad Libs.
-我不想玩了  -不好玩了
- I gotta go. - Funs over.
等等  如果遵守规则
Wait, guys, if we follow the rules...
一样好玩  而且才有意义啊
...it's still fun and it means something.
我要闪人了
I'm going to take off.
有规则才好
Guys, rules are good!
不守规则怎么会好玩
Rules help control the fun.